- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
♪ ♪
- [militaristic grunting]
- [军国主义的咕哝声]
Now, we all know
what this day is.
现在，我们都知道
今天是什么日子。
- Today is the day
when Plankton tries to steal
- 今天就是这一天
当浮游生物试图偷窃时
the Krabby Patty formula, sir!
蟹黄派配方，先生！
- Like he does every day.
- 就像他每天所做的那样。
- But this time,
he's not going to catch me
- 但这一次，
他不会抓住我的
with me spatula down!
[laughs]
跟我一起铲下去！
[笑]
Ooh?
[laughs]
哦？
[笑]
SpongeBob
海绵宝宝
you're on guard duty, boy!
你正在值班，孩子！
- Yes, sir, Mr. Krabs!
- 是的，先生，蟹老板！
Yah!
啊！
- And I'll go undercover.
- 我会去卧底。
[snoring]
[打鼾]
- Hm?
- Hut, two, three, four!
- 嗯？
- 小屋，二，三，四！
Hut, two, three, four!
小屋，二，三，四！
♪ Krabby Patties are the best ♪
♪ 蟹肉饼是最好吃的 ♪
♪ They'll put hair
on your chest ♪
♪ 他们会把头发
在你胸口♪
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
Oh!
哦！
- [falteringly]
♪ Krabby Patties are the best ♪
- [支吾其词]
♪ 蟹肉饼是最好吃的 ♪
♪ They'll put hairs...
into your nest ♪
♪ 他们会把头发...
进入你的巢穴♪
- [yawns]
- [哈欠]
Ow.
噢。
- Any sign of Plankton?
- 有浮游生物的迹象吗？
- Uh, afraid not, Mr. Krabs.
- 呃，恐怕不会，蟹老板。
- Maybe he's on vacation.
- 也许他正在度假。
- Don't be silly!
- 别傻了！
We always take
our trips together,
我们总是采取
我们一起旅行，
to keep an eye on each other.
互相关注。
What's taking that crook
so long?
那个骗子怎么了
这么久？
[jaunty accordion music]
[欢快的手风琴音乐]
Hm...
Maybe the door is stuck.
嗯...
也许门被卡住了。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
♪ ♪
Ah, for--these customers
are blocking the way!
啊，对于——这些顾客
挡住了路！
[yelling]
[大喊]
♪ ♪
- [sighs]
There we go.
- [叹气]
我们开始吧。
Nice, open path.
不错，开放的道路。
Hm?
Mm...
嗯？
毫米...
Hey!
Well, maybe he just needs
嘿！
好吧，也许他只是需要
a little incentive.
一点激励。
[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
[fanfare]
[chuckles]
[大张旗鼓]
[笑声]
There we go.
我们开始吧。
[stealthy jazz music]
[隐秘的爵士乐]
Oh.
哦。
Maybe he doesn't want
me formula anymore.
也许他不想
我的公式了。
[gasps]
[喘气]
He took the bait!
他上钩了！
We're going to red alert!
我们要进入红色警报了！
[alarmed music]
[惊慌的音乐]
[hubbub]
[尘嚣]
♪ ♪
Batten down the hatches!
关闭舱门！
Furl the deck!
卷起甲板！
Stop that greedy green goober!
停止那个贪婪的绿色家伙！
- [panting]
- [气喘吁吁]
Oh.
哦。
- [sighs]
Ow.
- [叹气]
噢。
♪ ♪
- Doggone it.
- 完蛋了。
Can I get some ketchup
over here?
我可以买点番茄酱吗
在这里？
Please?
请？
- False alarm.
- 误报。
all: Whoa!
全体：哇！
Oof!
钱币！
[all groaning]
[全都呻吟]
- Closing time!
- 关门时间！
[jaunty music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
- And just where
do you think
- 就在哪里
你认为
you two are going?
你们两个要去吗？
- It's customary
to go home at closing time.
- 这是习惯
关门时间回家。
- Aren't you going home,
Mr. Krabs?
- 你不回家吗
蟹老板？
- [laughing]
Oh, I'm not budging.
- [笑]
哦，我不让步。
Plankton is gonna
try something.
浮游生物将会
尝试一些东西。
I don't know when.
I don't know where.
我不知道什么时候。
我不知道在哪里。
- Probably... here.
- 可能...在这里。
- Well, yeah.
But when he does,
- 嗯，是的。
但当他这么做的时候，
I'll be waiting for him.
我会等他。
[laughs]
[笑]
I'll be waiting right here.
我就在这里等着。
- Morning!
Hm?
- 早晨！
嗯？
I guess Mr. Krabs
went home after all.
我猜是蟹老板
毕竟回家了。
- No, I'm still here...
- 不，我还在这里……
Waiting for
that blasted Plankton!
等待
那该死的浮游生物！
both: Gah!
两人：啊！
[disconcerting scales]
[令人不安的尺度]
- Yeah, I'll take--
- Me patty formula?
- 是的，我会接受--
- 我的肉饼配方？
Huh?
I knew it!
啊？
我就知道！
You in there, Plankton?
[grunts angrily]
你在里面吗，浮游生物？
[愤怒地咕哝]
- Mr. Krabs,
that's not Plankton!
- 蟹老板先生，
那不是浮游生物！
- I will never set foot
in this establishment again!
-我永远不会踏足
再次来到这个机构！
From now on,
I'm using the drive-through!
从现在开始，
我用的是直通车！
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
- [humming contentedly]
- [满足地哼哼]
Whoa!
- Aha!
哇！
- 啊哈！
Trying to to sneak
a Krabby Patty to Plankton, eh?
试图偷偷摸摸
蟹肉饼到浮游生物，是吗？
- But Eugene, it's just
a to-go order.
- 但是尤金，这只是
外带订单。
- [mocking gibberish]
- [嘲笑的胡言乱语]
Well, from now on,
all patties are to be eaten
嗯，从现在开始，
所有的肉饼都要吃掉
on the premises!
在现场！
- What are you gonna do now,
ban pockets?
- 你现在要做什么
禁止口袋？
- Capital idea,
Mr. Squidward.
- 资本理念，
章鱼哥先生。
There'll be a $50-a-barrel
surcharge from now on.
每桶价格为 50 美元
即日起加收附加费。
[runaway music]
[失控的音乐]
Whoa, hey,
slow down there, Grampa.
哇，嘿，
慢点儿，爷爷。
Let's just see here.
我们就看这里吧。
Aha!
啊哈！
Another one
of Plankton's spies!
另一个
浮游生物的间谍！
- I just wanted some for later.
- 我只是想要一些供以后使用。
- You're banned!
- 你被禁止了！
♪ ♪
Hm...
嗯...
So Plankton's recruiting
所以 Plankton 的招募
baby burglars now!
现在是小偷了！
- [cries]
- [哭声]
- You're banned!
- 你被禁止了！
You!
You're banned! You're banned!
你！
你被禁止了！你被禁止了！
Banned!
禁止！
- Ah...
- Banned!
- 啊...
- 禁止！
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
[unhinged string music]
[疯狂的弦乐]
You're all banned!
你们都被禁止了！
[gibbering]
[胡言乱语]
- Mr. Krabs, I don't think
Plankton's coming.
- 蟹老板先生，我不认为
浮游生物来了
- Nonsense.
- 废话。
[knocking]
[gasps]
[敲门声]
[喘气]
See?
It's that stinker Plankton now.
看？
现在是那个臭浮游生物了。
What do you want?
你想要什么？
- Uh...
A Krabby Patty?
- 呃...
蟹肉饼？
- Why?
- I'm hungry.
- 为什么？
- 我饿了。
- Mr. Krabs, that's just Sandy.
- 蟹老板，那是桑迪。
- I'm not falling for it.
- 我不会上当的。
That's the worst squirrel suit
I've ever seen.
这是最差的松鼠套装
我曾经见过。
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
[gibbering]
[胡言乱语]
- Do you think Mr. Krabs
is acting... strange?
- 你认为蟹老板先生
行为……很奇怪吗？
- [manic gibbering, laughter]
- [狂躁的胡言乱语，笑声]
- He seems fine to me.
- 他对我来说似乎很好。
- Maybe we should postpone
-也许我们应该推迟
our plans for tonight.
我们今晚的计划。
- Plans?
Aha!
- 计划？
啊哈！
You're both working
for Plankton!
你们俩都在工作
为了浮游生物！
Get out of me restaurant,
滚出我的餐厅，
you tricky treacherous
traitors!
你这个狡猾奸诈的人
叛徒！
[both groaning]
[两人都呻吟]
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
- I know you're in here,
Plankton.
- 我知道你在这里
浮游生物。
Where you hiding?
你躲哪儿了？
- I'm right here
- 我就在这里
at the Chum Bucket!
在密友桶里！
Come on down
下来吧
and try our new Chum Nuggets.
并尝试我们新推出的 Chum Nuggets。
- Heh.
Whew.
- 呵呵。
呼。
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
Oh.
[chuckles]
哦。
[笑声]
Just a--just a cup.
只是一个——只是一个杯子。
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- Ah!
Oh?
- 啊！
哦？
[maniacal laughter]
[疯狂的笑声]
Ah!
啊!
[dramatic music]
[戏剧音乐]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
[gibbering]
[胡言乱语]
♪ ♪
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
Get ahold of yourself.
把握好自己。
[sighs]
[叹气]
I'm starting to see things.
[laughs]
我开始看清事情了。
[笑]
[maniacal laughter]
[疯狂的笑声]
- [screams, gibbers]
- [尖叫声，胡言乱语]
Huh?
啊？
[suspenseful music]
[悬疑音乐]
♪ ♪
Those two ARE
那两个是
working for Plankton!
为浮游生物工作！
[gasps]
[喘气]
♪ ♪
- Ow.
- 噢。
- Me own daughter?
- 我自己的女儿？
♪ ♪
Oh, not Old Man Jenkins!
哦，不是老詹金斯！
[cries]
[哭声]
Everyone really is
out to get you.
大家确实是
出来找你。
Aren't they, my little formula?
不是吗，我的小公式？
[doorbell rings]
[门铃响]
- Mr. Krabs?
- 蟹老板？
[stiltedly] You have got
to come with me
[生硬地]你已经得到了
跟我来
to... The Chum Bucket,
到...密友桶，
for Plankton
has kidnapped Squidward.
对于浮游生物
绑架了章鱼哥。
- Oh, so that's
Plankton's evil plan?
- 哦，原来如此
浮游生物的邪恶计划？
He wants me formula
as ransom!
他要我配方
作为赎金！
What do we do?
我们该怎么办？
What?
What's that?
什么？
那是什么？
Oh, that's just brilliant!
哦，那真是太棒了！
Hold on a minute.
等一下。
I'll go get the ransom.
我去拿赎金。
Oh, you want a Krabby Patty,
do you?
哦，你想要一个蟹肉饼，
你呢？
Well, I'll give you
a Krabby Patty.
嗯，我给你
蟹肉饼。
[laughs maniacally]
[疯狂地笑]
Oh!
哦！
Ooh?
哦？
[laughs evilly]
[邪恶地笑]
Okay, let's go
rescue Squidward.
好吧，我们走吧
营救章鱼哥。
[laughs]
[笑]
[mysterious orchestral music]
【神秘的管弦乐】
- [muffled speech]
- [低声说话]
- [laughs evilly]
- [邪恶地笑]
Surprised, Krabs?
蟹蟹们，惊讶吗？
- Not at all, Sheldon.
- 一点也不，谢尔顿。
I knew you were
up to something.
我知道你是
做某事。
- Oh, yeah?
- 哦，是吗？
How about now?
现在怎么样？
all: Surprise!
全体：惊喜！
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
[confused noises]
[混乱的声音]
- Oh, come, Krabs.
- 哦，来吧，蟹蟹。
It's the anniversary
of the first time
这是周年纪念日
第一次
I tried to steal
your Krabby Patty formula!
我试图偷窃
你的蟹黄派配方！
- So we threw you
a surprise party.
- 所以我们把你扔了
一个惊喜派对。
- You mean you weren't
working for Plankton?
- 你的意思是你不是
为浮游生物工作？
- Of course not, Mr. Krabs.
- 当然不是，蟹老板。
- Oh, I shouldn't have
suspected you, SpongeBob.
- 哦，我不应该
怀疑你了，海绵宝宝。
Whew.
Won't need these anymore.
呼。
不再需要这些了。
[laughs]
[笑]
- Oh, boy, Krabby Patties!
- 哦，天哪，蟹肉饼！
- Yee-haw!
- 哎呀！
[excited hubbub]
[兴奋的喧哗]
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
No!
Don't eat the patties!
不！
别吃肉饼！
- Huh?
- Gotcha.
- 啊？
- 明白了。
[laughs]
[笑]
[gibbers]
[胡言乱语]
[energetic music]
[充满活力的音乐]
Ah!
啊!
♪ ♪
Whew.
呼。
Ah, tartar sauce!
啊，塔塔酱！
[groans]
[呻吟]
[screams]
[尖叫声]
♪ ♪
[all oohing]
[全都欢呼]
♪ ♪
Yay.
耶。
[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
♪ ♪
[excited chatter]
[兴奋的喋喋不休]
- A little help here!
- 这里有一点帮助！
- Did you enjoy
the surprise party, Mr. Krabs?
- 你喜欢吗
蟹老板，惊喜派对？
- Eh, I'll tell you
in a second.
- 呃，我告诉你
一秒钟。
- [grunts]
Huh?
- [咕哝]
啊？
[angelic chorus]
[天使合唱]
Ooh, that fool Krabs
哦，螃蟹那个傻瓜
left the Krabby Patty formula
behind!
留下了蟹黄派的配方
落后了！
[chuckles]
[笑声]
[nervous vocalization]
Mommy.
[紧张发声]
妈妈。
[ukulele music]
[尤克里里音乐]
Ooh.
哦。
- Yes, boyo.
I enjoyed it very much.
- 是的，男孩。
我非常喜欢它。
[laughs]
[笑]